Guide to the Baptist Church of Tyrone and Jersey record book,1848-1872.
Baptist Church of Tyrone and Jersey record book,1848-1872
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Baptist Church of Tyrone and Jersey record book, 1848-1872.
6075
Baptist Church of Tyrone and Jersey (Tyrone, N.Y.)
1 reel microfilm.
Microfilm.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Membership lists for male and female members (1860, 1866); church covenant and special meeting minutes (1848-1872) which deal with discipline and the appointment of pastors.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
This church was constituted as the Baptist Church of Jersey on November 22, 1815 with twelve members. One of the members, Phineas Fullerton was licensed to preach, and supplied the pulpit part time for a few years, but in 1818 he was excluded for intemperance. The Elder Thomas Brown supplied the church until 1824. In 1823 the name was changed to the Jersey and Tyrone Church, under which name it incorporated in 1826. In 1861 "Jersey" was dropped.
The church occupied a union church half-time from its construction in 1830 until erection of a church in West Village in 1849. The union edifice burned in 1851. See The History of Schuyler County p. 221 for a list of pastors and statistics from 1879.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Volume includes membership lists for male and female members (1860, 1866), church covenant and special meeting minutes (1848-1872) which deal with discipline, the appointment of pastors, accepting and dismissing members, and the appointment of representatives to the association, and the peace of the church. Items of note include:
5 p., List of male members with remarks. 1860.
8 p., List of female members with remarks. 1860.
5 p., List of male members with remarks. 1866.
8 p., List of female members with remarks. 1866.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Baptist Church of Tyrone and Jersey (Tyrone, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Baptists--New York (State)--Tyrone.; Church discipline--New York (State)--Tyrone.
Places:
Schuyler County (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Tyrone (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Minutes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Record of Baptist Church of Tyrone and Jersey
  - August 19, 1848
    First meeting.
  - 1848
    Plans to build a meeting house.
  - February 1849
    Three baptisms.
  - December 1849
    Meeting house ready for use.
  - February 2, 1850
    Decision of April 30, 1847 regarding secret societies is rescinded.
  - March - April 1854
    Revival.
  - April 22, 1854
    The church calls a council to solve difficulty with an elder, charged with lyings
  - May 17, 1854
    Council expels and defrocks the elder, a former pastor.
  - August 1, 1858
    Sister expelled for adultery.
  - March 17, 1860
    The church considers buying 4 parsonage.
  - February 21, 1863
    Resolution on dancing.
  - April 8, 1866
    Many new members.
  - August 20, 1870
    Statistics on membership are included after 1869.
  - February 3, 1872
    Last meeting.
    Loose notes.
  - June 18, 1979
    Program for the Tyrone United Methodist Church.